<sect1 id="bugs">
	<title>Reporting bugs</title>
<indexterm><primary>Bugs</primary><secondary>reporting</secondary></indexterm>
	<para>When reporting bugs, please specify <application>DataparkSearch</application> version
and provide us as much information about your problem as
possible. Such information as your platform and OS details, database
version, database statistics like number of URLs in database or
probably count of records in different tables would be very helpful to
find and fix possible bugs. </para>

	<para>Please, submit bug reports using our <ulink url="http://www.dataparksearch.org/cgi-bin/bt.pl">Bug Reporting System</ulink>
at <ulink url="http://www.dataparksearch.org/">DataparkSearch web site</ulink>.  
Please do not send reports to mailing list or to personal authors addresses!</para>

	<sect2 id="bugs-current">
		<title>Currently known bugs</title>
		<para>Use DataparSearch <ulink
					     url="http://code.google.com/p/dataparksearch/issues/list">Bug Reporting System</ulink> to view active and fixed bug statistics. 
As well, you can use this system to submit new bug-reports and proposals for new feature or improvements</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="bugs-core">
		<title>Core dump reports</title>
		<para>If indexer or <filename>search.cgi</filename>
die during their work and produce core, it would be very helpful to
send us gdb (The GNU Debugger) output. To do this, please make the
following steps. Make sure you have <application>DataparkSearch</application> built with <option>--with-debug</option> option for configure. 
If not, please rebuild it with this option and repeat the command leads to core dump.
Then, e.g. your binary is "indexer" and core file name is
<filename>indexer.core</filename> (or may be just
<filename>core</filename> on some platforms).</para>

		<para>Run GNU Debugger with executable as the first argument and with  core file as the second:</para>
		<para>
			<userinput>
gdb indexer indexer.core
</userinput>
		</para>
		<para>Some information about the crash location will appear:
		<programlisting>
Core was generated by `indexer'.
Program terminated with signal 8, Floating point exception.
Reading symbols from /usr/lib/libc.so.3...done.
Reading symbols from /usr/libexec/ld-elf.so.1...done.
#0  0x80483f3 in main () at indexer.c:4
4               printf("%d",0/0);
</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>Then type <literal>thread apply all backtrace</literal> command:
		<programlisting>
(gdb) thread apply all bt
#0  0x80483f3 in main () at indexer.c:4
#1  0x804837d in _start ()
</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>Send us either first and second outputs or just a screenshot of gdb session.</para>
	</sect2>
</sect1>
