<sect1 id="categories">
	<title>Categories</title>
<indexterm><primary>Categories</primary></indexterm>

	<para>There is a categories editor written in <!--PHP3 and--> Perl. You can
get it in <filename>perl/cat_ed/</filename> subdirectory of <application>DataparkSearch</application>
installation.</para>
	<para>Categories are similar to tag feature, but nested. So you can have one category inside another and so on.</para>
	<para>Basic points:
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>there are up to 6 nested levels;</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>every level occupies 2 hex or 36 base digits;</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>parameter for setting category is
<parameter>path</parameter>, which can be empty (means root category)
or up to 10 chars long (means deepest category).</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
        </para>
	<para>You can also set up symlinks, e.g. categories that are
actually links to other categories. <literal>link</literal> database
field is used for that. In the symlink last two characters should be
@@. In example above Moto-&gt;BMW is a link to Auto-&gt;BMW.</para>

	<para>First notice that category in the server table is set to be
11 characters long. This means you can use a valid character to keep
track of categories. If you are going to keep a category tree of any
size, then I would suggest using the category editor. But anyways, here's how it works.
</para>

	<para>You can use either the tag column or the category column
in the server for the same thing. Or you can categorize a site in two
different ways. For example you could keep track of sites that are
owned by a certain company and then categorize them as well. You could
use the tag option to keep of ownership and use the category option
for categories. When I explain the category option, it goes the same
for the tag option. </para>

	<para>A category can be broken down any way you choose. But
for it to work with the category editor, I believe for now, you have
to use two characters for each level. If you use the category editor
you have the choice to use a hex number going from 0-F or a 36 base
number going from 0-Z. Therefore a top-level category like 'Auto'
would be 01. If it has a subcategory like 'Ford', then it would be 01
(the parent category) and then 'Ford' which we will give 01. Put those
together and you get 0101. If 'Auto' had another subcategory named
'VW', then its id would be 01 because it belongs to the 'Ford'
category and then 02 because it's the next category. So its id would
be 0102. If VW had a sub category called 'Engine' then it's id would
start at 01 again and it would get the 'VW' id 02 and 'Auto' id of 01,
making it 010201.</para>

	<para>If you want to search for sites under that category then
you pass it <literal>cat=010201</literal> in the url...so create a
select box and give like that:
	<programlisting>
&lt;OPTION value="01"&gt;AUTO
&lt;OPTION value="0101"&gt;Ford
</programlisting>
	</para>
	<para>and so on...</para>

<note><para>For dbmode cache you need to have the following section defined in your
<filename>sections.conf</filename> file:
<programlisting>
Section category 0 32 single
</programlisting>
i.e. in overall you need to have the section 'category' defined with non-zero maximum length.
</para>
</note>


<sect2 id="category_cmd">
<title><command>Category</command> command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>Category</secondary></indexterm>
<programlisting>
Category &lt;string&gt;
</programlisting>
<para>
You may distribute documents between nested categories. Category
is a string in hex number notation. You may have up to 6 levels with
256 members per level. Empty category means the root of category tree.
Take a look into <xref linkend="categories"/> for more information.
<programlisting>
# This command means a category on first level:
Category AA
# This command means a category on 5th level:
Category FFAABBCCDD
</programlisting>
</para>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="categoryif_cmd">
<title><command>CategoryIf</command> command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CategoryIf</secondary></indexterm>
<programlisting>
CategoryIf &lt;category&gt; [Match|NoMatch] [NoCase|Case] [String|Regex] [loose] &lt;section&gt; &lt;arg&gt; [&lt;arg&gt; ... ]
</programlisting>
<para>
Mark document by &lt;category&gt; category, if the value of <option>section</option> match <option>arg</option> pattern given.
The meaning of first three optional parameters is exactly the same 
as for the <command>Allow</command> command (see <xref linkend="allow_cmd"/>). Optional parameter <option>loose</option> specify
to do not override the category value if it has been already set from server parameters.
</para>
<para>Example
<programlisting>
CategoryIf 010F regex Title "JOB ID"
</programlisting>
</para>
</sect2>


  <sect2 id="cattable">
    <title>Loading categories table</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CategoryTable</secondary></indexterm>
    <para>When the command 
<programlisting>
CategoryTable mysql://user:pass@host/dbname/tablename[?charset=CHARSET]
</programlisting>
is specified, <application>indexer</application> loads categories information from given <literal>tablename</literal> SQL-table. 
Check the structure of <option>categories</option> table in <filename>create/mysql/create.txt</filename> file. 
If there is no structure example for your database, take it as an example.</para>

    <para>You may use several <command>CategoryTable</command> commands to load categories information from different tables.
In such case, the values of <option>rec_id</option> field must be unique for all these tables.
</para>
  </sect2>

<sect2 id="flushcattable">
  <title>FlushCategoryTable command
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>FlushCategoryTable</secondary></indexterm>
</title>
<para>
This command deletes all records from <option>categories</option> table.
Use this command to delete outdated data before loading new data into <option>categories</option> table 
with <command>CategoryTable</command> commands.
</para>
</sect2>



</sect1>
