<sect2 id="data-acq">
	<title>Data acquisition</title>
<indexterm><primary>Data acquisition</primary></indexterm>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>ActionSQL</secondary></indexterm>

<para>With <command>ActionSQL</command> command you can execute SQL-queries with document related data while indexing.
The syntax of <command>ActionSQL</command> command is as follow:
<programlisting>
ActionSQL [add | update | delete] &lt;section&gt; &lt;pattern&gt; &lt;sql-template&gt; [&lt;dbaddr&gt;]
</programlisting>
where &lt;section&gt; is the name of document section to check for regex pattern &gt;pattern&gt; match. If a match is found then the &lt;sql-template&gt; is filled with regex meta-variables $1-$9 as well with search template meta-variables (as for example, $(Title), $(Last-Modified), etc.) to form a sql-query, which is executed in the first DBAddr defined in indexer.conf file. If the optional &lt;dbaddr&gt; paramater of ActionSQL command is set, a new connection is set according this DBAddr and sql-query is executed in this connection.
</para>

<para>One of options <option>add</option>, <option>update</option> or <option>delete</option> specify when this command is executed, on indexinf of a new document, 
on reindexing of a document or on delettion of a document.
If none of such option specified, the <option>add</option> option is assumed by default.
</para>

<para>Thus you can use ActionSQL commands to mind and collect the data on pages while indexing. 
For example, the following commands collect phone numbers (in Russian local notation) along with titles of pages where these phone numbers have been discovered:
<programlisting>
ActionSQL add body "\(([0-9]{3})\)[ ]*([0-9]{3})[- \.]*([0-9]{2})[- \.]*([0-9]{2})" "INSERT INTO phonedata(phone,title,id)VALUES('+7$1$2$3$4','$(title)',$(dp_id))"
ActionSQL update body "\(([0-9]{3})\)[ ]*([0-9]{3})[- \.]*([0-9]{2})[- \.]*([0-9]{2})" "UPDATE phonedata SET phone='+7$1$2$3$4',title='$(title)' WHERE id=$(dp_id)"
ActionSQL delete url "." "DELETE FROM phonedata WHERE id=$(dp_id)"
</programlisting>
</para>

</sect2>
