<sect2 id="ispell">
	<title>Ispell</title>
<indexterm><primary>Ispell</primary></indexterm>

	<para>When <application>DataparkSearch</application> is used with ispell support enabled, it automatically
extend search query by all grammatical forms of the query words. E.g. search front-end will try to
find the word "test" if "testing" or "tests" is given in search
query.</para>

	<sect3 id="typesispellfiles">
		<title>Two types of ispell files</title>
		<para><application>DataparkSearch</application> understands two types of ispell
files: affixes and dictionaries. Ispell affixes file contains rules
for words and has approximately the following format:
<programlisting>
Flag V:
       E   &gt; -E, IVE      # As in create&gt; creative
      [^E] &gt; IVE          # As in prevent &gt; preventive
Flag *N:
       E   &gt; -E, ION      # As in create &gt; creation
       Y   &gt; -Y, ICATION  # As in multiply &gt; multiplication
     [^EY] &gt; EN           # As in fall &gt; fallen
</programlisting>
</para>


		<para>Ispell dictionary file contains words themselves and has the following format:
<programlisting>
wop/S
word/DGJMS
wordage/S
wordbook
wordily
wordless/P
</programlisting>
</para>
	</sect3>
	<sect3 id="using-ispell">
		<title>Using Ispell</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>Affix</secondary></indexterm>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>Spell</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>To make <application>DataparkSearch</application> support ispell you must
specify <command>Affix</command> and <command>Spell</command> commands in <filename>search.htm</filename>
file. The format of commands:
		<programlisting>
Affix [lang] [charset] [ispell affix file name]
Spell [lang] [charset] [ispell dictionary filename]
</programlisting>
</para>
		<para>The first parameter of both commands is two
letters language abbreviation. The second is ispell files charset.
The third one is filename. File names are relative to <application>DataparkSearch</application>
<literal>/etc</literal> directory. Absolute paths can be also
specified.</para>

		<note>
			<para>Simultaneous loading of several languages is supported, e.g.:
			<programlisting>
Affix en iso-8859-1 en.aff
Spell en iso-8859-1 en.dict
Affix de iso-8859-1 de.aff
Spell de iso-8859-1 de.dict
</programlisting>
</para>
			<para>Will load support for both English and German languages.</para>
		</note>
		<para>If you use <literal>searchd</literal>, add the same commands to <filename>searchd.conf</filename>.</para>
		<para>When <application>DataparkSearch</application> is used with ispell support it
is recommended to use <literal>searchd</literal>, especially for
several languages support. Otherwise the starting time of
<filename>search.cgi</filename> increases.</para>

	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="addwords-dict">
		<title>Customizing dictionary</title>
		<para>It is possible that several rare words are found
in your site which are not in ispell dictionaries. In such case, an entry with longest match suffix is taking
	  to produce word forms.</para>

<para>But you can also create the
list of such words in plain text file with the following format (one
word per line):
		<programlisting>
rare.dict:
----------
webmaster
intranet
.......
www
http
---------
			</programlisting>
</para>
		<para>You may also use ispell flags in this file (for
ispell flags refer to ISpell documentation). This will allow not
writing the same word with different endings to the rare words file,
for example "webmaster" and "webmasters". You may choose the word
which has the same changing rules from existing ispell dictionary and
just to copy flags from it. For example, English dictionary has this
line:</para>

		<para>
			<literal>postmaster/MS</literal>
		</para>
		<para>So, webmaster with MS flags will be probably OK:</para>
		<para>
			<literal>webmaster/MS</literal>
		</para>
		<para>Then copy this file to <filename>/etc</filename> directory of
<application>DataparkSearch</application> and add this file by <command>Spell</command> command in 
<application>DataparkSearch</application> configuration:</para>

		<para>During next reindexing using of all documents
new words will be considered as words with correct spelling. The only
really incorrect words will remain.</para>

	</sect3>


<sect3 id="where-to-get-ispell">
<title>Where to get Ispell files</title>

<para>You may find ispell files for many of languages at
<ulink url="http://fmg-www.cs.ucla.edu/geoff/ispell-dictionaries.html">this page</ulink>.
</para>

<para>For Japanese language there exist quasi-ispell files suitable for use with <application>DataparkSearch</application> only.
You may get this data from <ulink url="http://www.dataparksearch.org/">our web site</ulink> or from one of our mirrors.
See <xref linkend="get"/>.
</para>


</sect3>


<sect3 id="quffix">
<title>Query words modification</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>Quffix</secondary></indexterm>
	<para><programlisting>
Quffix [lang] [charset] [ispell-like suffix file name]
</programlisting>
The <command>Quffix</command> command is similar to <command>Affix</command> command described above, except that these rules apply to the query words, bot not to the normal word forms
as it is done for <command>Affix</command> command. The file loaded with this command must contain only suffix rules (in terms of ispell affix files).
</para>
<para>This command is suitable, for example, to specify the rules to switch from one part of speech to an another for the Russian language when it is appropriate.
</para>

</sect3>

</sect2>
