<sect2 id="mirror">
	<title>Mirroring</title>
<indexterm><primary>Mirroring</primary></indexterm>

	<para id="mirrorroot-cmd">
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>MirrorRoot</secondary></indexterm>
You may specify a path to root dir to enable sites mirroring
	<programlisting>
MirrorRoot /path/to/mirror
</programlisting>
	</para>
	<para id="mirrorheadersroot-cmd">
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>MirrorHeadersRoot</secondary></indexterm>
You may specify as well root directory of mirrored document's headers indexer will store HTTP headers to local disk too.
	<programlisting>
MirrorHeadersRoot /path/to/headers
</programlisting>
	</para>
	<para id="mirrorperiod-cmd">
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>MirrorPeriod</secondary></indexterm>
You may specify period during which earlier mirrored files will be used while indexing instead of real downloading.
	<programlisting>
MirrorPeriod &lt;time&gt;
</programlisting>
	</para>
	<para>It is very useful when you do some experiments with
<application>DataparkSearch</application> indexing the same hosts and do not want much traffic
from/to Internet. If MirrorHeadersRoot is not specified and headers
are not stored to local disk then default Content-Type's given in
AddType commands will be used. Default value of the MirrorPeriod is
-1, which means <literal>do not use mirrored files</literal>.</para>
	<para>&lt;time&gt; is in the form
<literal>xxxA[yyyB[zzzC]]</literal> (Spaces are allowed between xxx
and A and yyy and so on) where xxx, yyy, zzz are numbers (can be
negative!). A, B, C can be one of the following:
	<programlisting>
		s - second
		M - minute
		h - hour
		d - day
		m - month
		y - year
</programlisting>
</para>
	<para>(these letters are the same as in strptime/strftime functions)</para>
	<para>Examples:
	<programlisting>
15s - 15 seconds
4h30M - 4 hours and 30 minutes
1y6m-15d - 1 year and six month minus 15 days
1h-10M+1s - 1 hour minus 10 minutes plus 1 second
</programlisting>
</para>
	<para>If you specify only number without any character, it is
assumed that time is given in seconds (this behavior is for
compatibility with versions prior to 3.1.7).</para>
	<para>The following command will force using local copies for one day:
	<programlisting>
MirrorPeriod 1d
</programlisting>
	</para>
	<para>If your pages are already indexed, when you re-index
with -a indexer will check the headers and only download files that
have been modified since the last indexing. Thus, all pages that are
not modified will not be downloaded and therefore not mirrored
either. To create the mirror you need to either (a) start again with a
clean database or (b) use the -m switch. </para>
	<para>You can actually use the created files as a full
featured mirror to you site. However be careful: indexer will not
download a document that is larger than MaxDocSize. If a document is
larger it will be only partially downloaded. If you site has no large
documents, everything will be fine.</para>
</sect2>
