<sect1 id="perf">
<indexterm><primary>Performance issues</primary></indexterm>
	<title><application>DataparkSearch</application> performance issues</title>

<para>The cache mode is the fastest <application>DataparkSearch</application>'s storage mode. Use it if
you need maximal search speed.
</para>

<para>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>ColdVar</secondary></indexterm>
If your <filename>/var</filename> directory isn't changed since the indexing has been finished, you may disable file locking using 
<command>"ColdVar yes"</command> command placed in <filename>search.htm</filename> (or in <filename>searchd.conf</filename>,
if <command>searchd</command> is used). This allow you to save some time on file locking.
</para>

<para>Using <userinput>UseCRC32URLId yes</userinput> command (see <xref linkend="usecrc32urlid_cmd"/>) allow to speed up indexing, but
small number of collisions is possible, especially on large database. 
</para>


<sect2 id="searchd-rec">
<title><command>searchd</command> usage recommendation</title>
<para>If you plan use ispell data, synonym or stopword lists, it's recommended setup
the <command>searchd</command> daemon for speed-up searches (See <xref linkend="searchd"/>). 
<command>searchd</command> daemon preload all these data and lists
and holds them in memory. This reduce average search query execution time.
</para>
<para>Also, <command>searchd</command> can preload url info data (20 bytes per URL indexed) and 
cache mode limits (4 or 8 bytes per URL depend on limit type). This allow reduce average search time.
</para>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="search-cache">
<title>Search results caching</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>Cache</secondary></indexterm>
<para><para>Use "<command>Cache yes</command>" command in your <filename>search.htm</filename> template (or in <filename>searchd.conf</filename> file, if
<application>searchd</application> is used) to enable search results cache. That allows to reduce significantly the answer time for repeating queries.</para>
<para>
If you use search results caching, please note you need to empty <filename>var/cache</filename> directory after each indexing/reindexing.
</para>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="mfs-rec">
<title>Memory based filesystem (mfs) usage recommendation</title>
<para>If you use cache storage mode and you have enough RAM on your PC, 
you may place <filename>/usr/local/dpsearch/var</filename>
directory on memory based filesystem (mfs). This allow speedup both indexing and searching.
</para>
<para>If you haven't enough RAM to fit  <filename>/usr/local/dpsearch/var</filename>, 
you may place on memory filesystem any of <filename>/usr/local/dpsearch/var/tree</filename>,
<filename>/usr/local/dpsearch/var/url</filename> or <filename>/usr/local/dpsearch/var/store</filename>
directories as well.
</para>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="urlinfo-cmd">
<title><command>URLInfoSQL</command> command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>URLinfoSQL</secondary></indexterm>
<para>For dbmode cache, you may use <command>URLInfoSQL no</command> command to disable storing URL Info into SQL database.
But using this command, you'll be unable to use limits by language and by Content-Type.
</para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="srvinfo-cmd">
<title><command>SRVInfoSQL</command>command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>SRVInfoSQL</secondary></indexterm>
<para>With the <command>SRVInfoSQL no</command> command you can switch off storing auxiliary data into "srvinfo" SQL-table.
In this case this table can not be used to load configuration with <command>LoadServerTable</command> command (See <xref linkend="srvtable-load"/>).
</para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="markforindex-cmd">
<title><command>MarkForIndex</command> command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>MarkForIndex</secondary></indexterm>
<para>By default, <application>DataparkSearch</application> are marking all URLs selected for indexing as indexed for 4 hours.
This prevent possible simultaneous indexing of the same URL by different indexer instance running. But for huge installation this feature
can take some time for processing. You may switch off this markage using <command>"MarkForIndex no"</command> in your 
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> file.
</para>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="checkinsertsql-cmd">
<title><command>CheckInsertSQL</command> command</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CheckInsertSQL</secondary></indexterm>
<para>By default, <application>DataparkSearch</application> trying to insert data into SQL database regardless it's already present there.
On some systems this raise some error loggings. To avoid such errors, 
you may enable additional checks, is the inserting data new, by specifying
<command>CheckInsertSQL yes</command> command in your <filename>indexer.conf</filename>.
</para>
</sect2>




	<sect2 id="perf-mysql">
		<title>MySQL performance</title>
		<para>MySQL users may declare <application>DataparkSearch</application> tables with
<option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE=1</option> option. This will make the updating
of indexes faster, as these are not logged to disk until the file is
closed. <option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE</option> excludes updating indexes on
disk at all. </para>
		<para>With it indexes are processed only in memory and
written onto disk as last resort, command <command>FLUSH TABLES
</command> or mysqld shutdown. This can take even minutes and
impatient user can <literal>kill -9 mysql server</literal> and break
index files with this.  Another downside is that you should run
<literal>myisamchk</literal> on these tables before you start mysqld
to ensure that they are okay if something killed mysqld in the
middle.</para>
		<para>Because of it we didn't include this table
option into default tables structure. However as the key information
can always be generated from the data, you should not lose anything by
using <option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE</option>. So, use this option for your
own risk.</para>
	</sect2>

<sect2 id="ares">
<title>Asynchronous resolver library</title>
<para>Using <ulink url="http://c-ares.haxx.se/">c-ares</ulink>, 
an asynchronous resolver library (dns/c-ares in FreeBSD ports collection), allow to perform DNS queries without blocking for every
indexing thread. Please note, this also increase the number of concurrent queries to your DNS server.
</para>
</sect2>

</sect1>
