<sect1 id="rel">
	<title>Relevance</title>
<indexterm><primary>Relevance</primary></indexterm>

	<sect2 id="rel-order">
		<title>Ordering documents</title>
		<para><application>DataparkSearch</application> by default sorts results first by <literal>relevency</literal>
and second by <literal>popularity rank</literal>.</para>
	</sect2>


<sect2 id="relevancy"><title>Relevance calculation</title>

<para>In indexing, <application>DataparkSearch</application> divides every document onto sections. A section is any part of the document, 
for example, for HTML documents this may be TITLE or META Description tag.</para>

<para>In addition to sections, some document factors are also take in account for relevance calculation: the average distance between
query words, the number of query word occurrences, the position of first occurrence of a query word, the difference between the
distribution of query word counts and the uniform distribution.</para>

<para>In searching, <application>DataparkSearch</application> compares every document found against an "ideal" document. The "ideal"
document should have query words in every section defined and should have also the predefined values of additional factors.</para>

<!--para>Relevance for every found document is calculated as 100% multiply by cosine of an angle formed by weights vector for request
and weights vector for document found. The number of vector coordinates is equal to multiplication of the number words forms in 
search query and the number of sections defined in <filename>indexer.conf</filename>. Every vector's coordinate is corresponds to
a word in search query that fit one of document section. The values of this coordinate is depends on weight for this section
defined by <option>wf</option> parameter (see <xref linkend="search-changeweight"/>)
and what this word is: exactly the same as in search query or it's word form or synonym.
And one more coordinate is equal to average distance between searched words in document. 
For query related vector this coordinate is equal to 0.
</para-->

<para id="numsections-cmd">
Since sections definition located only in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file, use
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>NumSections</secondary></indexterm> <command>NumSections</command>
command in <filename>searchd.conf</filename> or in <filename>search.htm</filename> to specify the number od section used.
By default, this value is 256. But note, <command>NumSections</command> do not affect document ordering, only the relevance value.
</para>

<table><title>Configure-time parameters to tune relevance calculation (switches for <command>configure</command>)</title>
	<tgroup cols="2">
	<tbody>
<row><entry><option>--enable-rel</option></entry>
<entry><para>This option enables "full", "fast" or "ultra" version of relevance calculation. Value by default: full (i.e. full relevance calculation).
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--disable-reldistance</option></entry>
<entry><para>This option disables accounting of average word distance for relevance calculation. Value by default: enabled.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--disable-relposition</option></entry>
<entry><para>This option disables accounting of first query word position for relevance calculation. Value by default: enabled.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--disable-relwrdcount</option></entry>
<entry><para>This option disables accounting of word counts for relevance calculation. Value by default: enabled.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-avgdist=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as the best average distance between words in document found.
Value by default: 464.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-bestpos=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as the best value of first word position in document found.
Value by default: 4.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-bestwrdcnt=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as the best number of each query word in document found. 
Value by default: 11.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-distfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as a factor for average word distance for relevance calculation. 
Value by default: 0.2.
</para></entry></row>
<row><entry><option>--with-lessdistfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as factor of average word distance in relevance calculation when average
distance is less than value specified with <option>--with-avgdist</option>.
Default value is <option>--with-distancefactor</option> multiply by 2.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-posfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as factor for difference between first query word position in document found and best position specified by <option>--with-bestpos</option> option. 
Value by default: 0.5.
</para></entry></row>
<row><entry><option>--with-lessposfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify <option>NUM</option> as factor of first word position in relevance calculation when it less than value
specified with <option>--with-bestpos</option>.
Default value is <option>--with-posfactor</option> multyply by 4.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-wrdcntfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as factor for difference between count of query words in document found
and the best value specified by <option>--with-bestwrdcnt</option> option. 
Value by default: 0.4.
</para></entry></row>
<row><entry><option>--with-lesswrdcntfactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify <option>NUM</option> as factor of word count in relevance calculation when this word count is less than
value specified with <option>--with-bestwrdcnt</option>.
Default value is <option>--with-wrdcntfactor</option> multiply by 10.
</para></entry></row>

<row><entry><option>--with-wrdunifactor=<option>NUM</option></option></entry>
<entry><para>This option specify the <option>NUM</option> as factor for difference of query word counts from uniform distribution. 
Value by default: 1.5.
</para></entry></row>

	</tbody>
	</tgroup>
</table>

<sect3 id="rel-full"><title>A full method of relevance calculation.</title>
<indexterm><primary>Relevance</primary><secondary><literal>full</literal> method</secondary></indexterm>
<para>Let <literal>x</literal> is the weighted sum of all sections. The weights for these sections are define by 
<option>wf</option> parameter (see <xref linkend="search-changeweight"/>). Let <literal>y</literal> is the weighted sum of
differences between values of additional factors of document found and corresponding values of additional factors of the "ideal"
document. And let <literal>xy</literal> is the weighted sum of sections where at least one query word has been found. Then value of
relevance for a document found is calculates as: <literal>0.5 * ( x + xy ) / (x + y)</literal>.
</para>
</sect3>

<sect3 id="rel-fast"><title>A fast method of relevance calculation.</title>
<indexterm><primary>Relevance</primary><secondary><literal>fast</literal> method</secondary></indexterm>
<para>Let <literal>x</literal> is the number of bits used in weighted values of all sections defined. Let <literal>y</literal> is
the weighted sum of differences between additional factors of document found and corresponding values of the "ideal" document.
And let <literal>xy</literal> is the number of bits where weighted values of sections of the "ideal" document are different to weighted
values of sections of document found. Then value of document relevance is calculates as: 
<literal>( x - xy ) / ( x + y )</literal>.
</para>
</sect3>


</sect2>


<sect2 id="poprank"><title>Popularity rank</title>
<indexterm><primary>Popularity rank</primary></indexterm>

<para id="poprankmethod-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankMethod</secondary></indexterm>
<application>DataparkSearch</application> support two methods for popularity rank calculation. A method used in previous versions
called &quot;Goo&quot;, and new method is called &quot;Neo&quot;. By default, the <literal>Goo</literal> method is used. To select
desired PopRank calculation method use <command>PopRankMethod</command> command:
<programlisting>
PopRankMethod Neo
</programlisting>
</para>

<para id="collectlinks-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CollectLinks</secondary></indexterm>
You need enable links collection by <command>CollectLinks yes</command> command in your 
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> file for <literal>Neo</literal> method and for full functionality
of <literal>Goo</literal> method.
But this slow down a bit indexing speed. By default, links collection is not enabled. 
</para>

<para id="poprankskipsamesite-cmd">By default, only intersite links (i.e. links from a page on 
one site to a page on an another site) are taken in account for the popularity rank calculation.
If you place
<command><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankSkipSameSite</secondary></indexterm>PopRankSkipSameSite no</command>
command in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file, <command>indexer</command> take all links for this purpose.
</para>

<para>You may assign initial value for page popularity rank using DP.PopRank META tag (see <xref linkend="htmlparser-meta"/>).
</para>


<sect3 id="Goo-poprank"><title>&quot;Goo&quot; popularity rank calculation method</title>

<para>
The popularity rank calculation is made in two stages. At first stage, the value of <option>Weight</option> parameter
for every server is divide by number of links from this server. Thus, the weight of one link from this server is calculated.
At second stage, for every page we find the sum of weights of all links pointed to this page. This sum is popularity rank for this page.
</para>

<para id="weight-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>ServerWeight</secondary></indexterm>
By default, the value of <option>Weight</option> parameter is equal to 1 for all servers indexed.
You may change this value by <command>ServerWeight</command> command in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file or
directly in <literal>server</literal> table, if you load servers configuration from this table.
</para>

<para id="poprankfeedback-cmd">If you place
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankFeedBack</secondary></indexterm>PopRankFeedBack yes</option>
command in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file, <command>indexer</command> will calculate site weights before page rank
calculation. To do that, <command>indexer</command> calculate sum of popularity rank for all pages from same site. If this sum will
great 1, the weight for site set to this sum, otherwise, site weight is set to 1.
</para>

<para id="poprankusetracking-cmd">If you place
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankUseTracking</secondary></indexterm>PopRankUseTracking yes</option>
command in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file, <command>indexer</command> will calculate site weight as the number of 
tracked queries with restriction on this site.
</para>

<para id="poprankuseshowcnt-cmd">If you place
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankUseShowCnt</secondary></indexterm>PopRankUseShowCnt yes</option>
command in <filename>search.htm</filename> (or <filename>searchd.conf</filename>) file, then for every result shown to user
corresponding <literal>url.shows</literal> value will be increased on 1, if relevance for this result is great or equal to
value specified by 
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankShowCntRatio</secondary></indexterm>PopRankShowCntRatio</option>
command (default value is 25.0).
If you place <option>PopRankUseShowCnt yes</option> in <filename>indexer.conf</filename> file, <command>indexer</command>
will add to url's PopularityRank the value of <literal>url.shows</literal> multiplied by value, specified in
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankShowCntWeight</secondary></indexterm>PopRankShowCntWeight</option>
command (default value is 0.01).
</para>

</sect3>

<sect3 id="Neo-poprank"><title>&quot;Neo&quot; popularity rank calculation method</title>
</sect3>

<para>For this method is supposed all pages are neurons and links between pages are links between neurons.
So it's possible use an error back-propagation algorithm to train this neural network. Popularity rank for a page is the 
activity level for corresponding neuron. See <ulink url="http://www.maxime.net.ru/doc/Neo-en.pdf">short description of The Neo 
Popularity Rank for web pages</ulink>.
</para>

<para>You may use
<option><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankNeoIterations</secondary></indexterm>PopRankNeoIterations</option>
command to specify the number of iterations of the Neo Popularity Rank calculation. Default value is 3.
</para>

<para><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>PopRankPostpone</secondary></indexterm>
By default, the Neo Popularity Rank is caclulated along with indexing. To speed up indexing, 
you may postpone Popularity Rank execution using <command>PopRankPostpone</command> command:
</para>
<programlisting>
PopRankPostpone yes
</programlisting>
<para>Then you may calculate the Neo Popularity Rank after indexing in same way as for method Goo, i.e.: 
<command>indexer -TR</command>
</para>

</sect2>




	<sect2 id="rel-bool">
		<title>Boolean search</title>
<indexterm><primary>Boolean search</primary><secondary>relevance</secondary></indexterm>

		<para>Please note that in case of boolean searching for two or more
words, you have to enter operators (&amp;, |, ~, AND, OR, NOT, NEAR, ALL, etc.). I.e. it is necessary
to enter <userinput>a &amp; book</userinput> instead of <userinput>a book</userinput>.
See also <xref linkend="search-bool"/>.
</para>

	</sect2>
	<sect2 id="rel-cwords">
		<title>Crosswords</title>
<indexterm><primary>Crosswords</primary></indexterm>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CrossWords</secondary></indexterm>

		<para>This feature allows to assign words between
&lt;a href="xxx"&gt; and &lt;/a&gt; also to a document this link leads
to, and the words from <userinput>alt</userinput> attribute of <userinput>img</userinput> tag to 
the picture this tag is pointed to. To enable Crosswords, please use
<command>CrossWords yes</command> command in
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> and
<filename>search.htm</filename>, and define <userinput>crosswords</userinput> section in <filename>sections.conf</filename> file.
</para>

<para><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>CrossWordsSkipSameSite</secondary></indexterm>
With the <command>CrossWordsSkipSameSite</command> command you can manage the collection of crosswords from the same site.
If the option <userinput>yes</userinput> is set (by default), the crosswords from the same site doen't collected. 
If you wish to collect such crosswords, you need to set <userinput>no</userinput> option explicitly:
<programlisting>
CrossWordsSkipSameSite no
</programlisting>
</para>

	</sect2>



<sect2 id="sea">
<indexterm><primary>Summary Extraction Algorithm, The</primary></indexterm>
<title>The Summary Extraction Algorithm (SEA)</title>
<indexterm><primary>SEA</primary><secondary>The Summary Extraction Algorithm</secondary></indexterm>
<indexterm><primary>Template variable</primary><secondary>$(sea)</secondary></indexterm>
<indexterm><primary>Document</primary><secondary>summary</secondary></indexterm>
<para><literal>The Summary Exctraction Algorith (SEA)</literal> builds the summary of three or more the most relevant sentences of the each
document indexed, if this document consists of six or more sentences. To enable this feature, add this command to your
<filename>seaction.conf</filename> file:
<programlisting>
Section sea x y
</programlisting>
where <option>x</option> - the number of section and <option>y</option> - the maximum length of this section value, 
leave 0,  if you do not want show this in result pages.
If you specify <option>y</option> non-zero, you may use <literal>$(sea)</literal> meta-variable in your search 
template to show the summary in result pages.
</para>

<para>Related configuration directives:
</para>
<para id="seasentenceminlen-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>SEASentenceMinLength</secondary></indexterm>
The <command>SEASentenceMinLength</command> command specify the minimal length of sentence to be used in summary construction
using the SEA. Default value: 64.
</para>
<para id="seasentences-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>SEASentences</secondary></indexterm>
The <command>SEASentences</command> command uses to specify the maximal number of sentences with length greater or equal to the value
specified by the <command>SEASentenceMinLength</command> command, which are used for summary construction in the SEA. Default value: 32.
Since the summary construction using SEA is nonlinear expensive (affects only indexing), 
you may adjust this value according to desired indexing performance.
</para>
<para id="seasections-cmd"><indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>SEASections</secondary></indexterm>
With <command>SEASections</command> command you can specify the list of document sections which are used to construct SEA summary.
By default, only the "body" section is used for SEA summary construction.
<programlisting>
SEASections "body, title"
</programlisting>
</para>



<para>This algorithm of automatic summary construction is based on ideas of Rada Mihalcea described in the paper 
<ulink url="http://www.cs.unt.edu/~rada/papers/mihalcea.ijcnlp05.pdf">Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau, 
An Algorithm for Language Independent Single and Multiple Document Summarization, 
in Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (IJCNLP), Korea, October 2005</ulink>.
</para>

<para>Differences in DataparkSearch's SEA:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Initial weights for graph edges are calculates as a measure of similarity between 
3-gram distributions of corresponding sentences.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Initial value for all graph vertexes is equal to the value of 1 / (number of sentences + 1) in the current implementation.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem><para>The Neo PopRank algorithm is used as ranking algorithm to iterate values assigned to vertexes.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>After indexing of document collection with this section defined, you may use $(sea) meta-variable in your 
template to show summary for a search result.</para>

</sect2>


	<!-- sect2 id="rel-dr">
		<title>$(Score) template variable</title>
		<para>
			<varname>$(Score)</varname> template variable displays number of words from the query found in a document.</para>
	</sect2 -->
</sect1>
