<sect1 id="srvtable">
  <title>Servers Table</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>ServerTable</secondary></indexterm>

  <para><application>DataparkSearch</application> has <command>ServerTable</command>
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> command. It allow load servers and filters configuration from SQL table. </para>

  <sect2 id="srvtable-load">
    <title>Loading servers table</title>
    <para>When <command>ServerTable mysql://user:pass@host/dbname/tablename[?srvinfo=infotablename]</command>
is specified, indexer will load
servers information from given <literal>tablename</literal> SQL table, and will load servers parameters
from given <literal>infotablename</literal> SQL table. If <literal>srvinfo</literal> parameter is not specified,
parameters will be loaded from <literal>srvinfo</literal> table. Check the structure for <literal>server</literal> and
<literal>srvinfo</literal> tables in <filename>create/mysql/create.txt</filename> file. If there is no
structure example for your database, take it as an example.</para>

    <para>You may use several <command>ServerTable</command> command to load servers information from different tables.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="srvtable-structure">
    <title>Servers table structure</title>
    <para>Servers table consists of all necessary fields which
describe servers parameters. Field names have correspondent
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> commands. For example, "period"
field corresponds "Period" <filename>indexer.conf</filename>
command. Default field values are the same with default
<filename>indexer.conf</filename> parameters.</para>

    <para>"gindex" field corresponds "Index" command. Name is slightly changed to avoid SQL reserved word usage.</para>

<para>Description for several fields see in <xref linkend="dbschema"/>.</para>

    <note>
      <para>Only those servers are read from the table where "active"
field has 1 value and "parent" field has 0 value. This is useful to allow users to submit new URLs
into servers table and give administrator a possibility to approve
added URLs.</para>

    </note>
  </sect2>

<sect2 id="flushsrvtable">
  <title>Flushing Servers Table</title>
<indexterm><primary>Command</primary><secondary>FlushServerTable</secondary></indexterm>

<para>
 Flush server.enabled to inactive for all server table records. 
Use this command to deactivate all command in servertable before load new from <filename>indexer.conf</filename>
or from other servertable.
</para>
</sect2>

</sect1>
